<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<tss:senteContainer version="1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.thirdstreetsoftware.com/SenteXML-1.0 SenteXML.xsd" xmlns:tss="http://www.thirdstreetsoftware.com/SenteXML-1.0" xmlns="http://www.thirdstreetsoftware.com/SenteXML-1.0" >
<tss:library>
<tss:references>
<tss:reference>
<tss:publicationType name="Book"/>
<tss:authors>
<tss:author role="Author"><tss:surname>Tamārī</tss:surname><tss:forenames>Salīm</tss:forenames><tss:initials></tss:initials></tss:author>
</tss:authors>
<tss:dates>
<tss:date type="Publication" year="2008"/>
<tss:date type="Entry" day="2" month="8" year="2018"/>
<tss:date type="Modification" day="8" month="8" year="2018"/>
</tss:dates>
<tss:characteristics>
<tss:characteristic name="publicationTitle">ʿām al-jarād: al-ḥarb al-ʿuẓma wa maḥw al-māḍī al-ʿUthmānī min Filasṭīn</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="abstractText">Consists primarily of Turjman's diary, p. 71-328.&lt;br&gt;# content&lt;br&gt;this is a full edition of Turjmān's diary unlike the English translation which presents only an excerpt (and hides this information in an endnote)&lt;br&gt;# critique&lt;br&gt;- some of the hijri dates are wrong and it could be an error not detected by the editor or one introduced by the editor&lt;br&gt;    + 10 Apr 1915 should be 26 Jum I 1333 instead of 15 Jum I  (92) as is evident from the following entry (94)&lt;br&gt;# Dairy entries&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;92&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-04-10, Sat&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- mentions that he bought a copy of the newspaper &amp;lt;title level=&quot;j&quot;&amp;gt;al-Muqtabas&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; and discussed with Khalīl Efendi Sakākīnī an article about two Muslim women from Damascus, who abandoned their children, who later died in an accident. Longer discussion on Muslim women &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;97&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-04-12, Mon: the lazy life in the Army&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- went to the military offices and was bored to death for the lack of work&lt;br&gt;- heard from some people in Ramallah that they could hear the bombardment of Jaffa [British naval bombardment]&lt;br&gt;- similar stories about the bombardment of Gaza&lt;br&gt;- but he is not sure if these stories are true because there are so many lies in this country and currently no telegramms or newspapers or any other means of getting news from Jaffa. And foreign newspapers don't make it into the country and nothing reaches &quot;us&quot; (i.e. him) but until the military censors (*al-sinsūr*) have read it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;98&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;120&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-04-20, Tue: Zionism and the hypocrisy of its adherents&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- went to the military offices and read in the first volume of Muḥammad Kurd ʿAlī's Arabic translation of the French book &amp;lt;title level=&quot;m&quot;&amp;gt;tārīkh al-ḥaḍāra&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;. I had convinced myself to read the entire volume this month and I cannot complete anything&lt;br&gt;- his father passed by and gave him £T 4 and £ 1 to buy three tankāt of fat (*samn*) from Abū Ḥasan al-Tayyān&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;121&quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;122&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;- news of a British plane having flown over Jaffa and dropped leaflets &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;124&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-04-21, Wed: the newspaper &quot;al-Ḥimāra&quot; scolding the Ottoman leadership&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- he got two issues of the newspaper &amp;lt;title level=&quot;j&quot;&amp;gt;al-Ḥimāra&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; from his father and read them. These issues scolded the Ottoman leadership of Ṭalaʿat Bey and &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;125&quot;/&amp;gt;  Enver Pasha&lt;br&gt;    + Tamārī identifies this as the newspaper &amp;lt;title level=&quot;j&quot;&amp;gt;al-Ḥimāra al-Qāhira&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; from Haifa, which was established in Sep 1911. Editors are Khalīl Zaqūt and Najīb Jānā&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;135&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-04-24, Sat: the military salary is insufficient to finance tobacco&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- information that on 14 Nīsān 1331 (1915-04-27) they will celebrate the anniversary of the accession of Mehmet V.  &lt;br&gt;- general complains about the financial situation of the Ottoman Empire &lt;br&gt;- he heard his father asking his mother about the meals for today and he learned &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;136&quot;/&amp;gt; that there will be neither lunch nor dinner.&lt;br&gt;- met Prof. Khalīl Sakākīnī, who invited him for dinner and they had a tasty broth of meat and lemon.&lt;br&gt;- smoked his last cigarette, getting desperate &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;137&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;- when he went out with Sakākīnī, they were approached by a poor and desperate woman, carrying a toddler and accompanied by two small children. She was beautiful and not older than 25 years. Asked Sakākīnī for help&lt;br&gt;    - she was married to a soldier drafted this week and had nothing to support her and her children. Iḥsān felt so sorry for her that he gave her all his money, amounting to only 4,5 metallik. &lt;br&gt;    - wouldn't it have been the duty of the Ottoman Empire to prevent such suffering and not declare this war?&lt;br&gt;- in the afternoon he received his monthly pay, which amounted to Ps 5 [sic!]. This is outrages and probably the lowest salary soldiers receive anywhere in the world. What can one do with Ps 5? Insufficient for tobacco, meat, or any of the daily necessities.&lt;br&gt;- all prisoners mentioned on 1915-04-02 were released. Reason for imprisonment unknown &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;138&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;### map of the battle field&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;139&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;meeting at the *al-madrasa al-waṭaniyya*, stories of combats between Ottoman and British airplanes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;184&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-05-09, Sun: ... war and inflation / high prices and locust and illnesses&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- various misfortunes visit us: war, high prices for food, locusts and illnesses. I don't know how to sleep at night and how to walk the suqs during the day and to talk under these conditions.&lt;br&gt;- no information on prices or any other specifics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;226&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-05-31, Mon: nothing to be found in the market but oranges to eat&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- went to the military offices and heard about the French naval bombardment of Jaffa and especially the gas works. rumours of 80 to 90 casualties.&lt;br&gt;- the locusts became so numerous that they event entered the city these days and if the government doesn't do anything we will die hungry these days&lt;br&gt;- for some days the price of vegetables is rising until the price reached &amp;lt;measureGrp&amp;gt;&amp;lt;measure commodity=&quot;currency&quot; unit=&quot;ops&quot; quantity=&quot;7.5&quot;&amp;gt;Ps 7&quot;20&amp;lt;/measure&amp;gt; per &amp;lt;measure commodity=&quot;cucumber&quot; unit=&quot;ratl&quot; quantity=&quot;1&quot;&amp;gt;raṭl of cucumbers&amp;lt;/measure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/measureGrp&amp;gt; but after some days nothing was to be found for food anyway. I couldn't find anything in the market today safe for oranges and some tomatoes and a tiny amount of cucumbers. anything else is not available.&lt;br&gt;- the abundance of oranges is due to the war preventing all exports to Britain. Therefore they are very cheap&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;227&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&amp;lt;pb n=&quot;228&quot;/&amp;gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;## 1915-06-09, Wed: &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- hadn't written for a whole week, provides a summary of events&lt;br&gt;- very hot weather prevents him from going out in the afternoon&lt;br&gt;- Fri:&lt;br&gt;    + the authorities closed down all shops and workshops in the city and made the people go out to the surrounding villages to fight the locust&lt;br&gt;    + the shop owners put their young children in charge to guard the shops [from looting]&lt;br&gt;    + the people (*ahālī*) could not go out into the streets anyway, because the police was looking for anyone evading the draft and sending them to fight the locust&lt;br&gt;    + but, of course, I knew that the authorities and the police would not be able to draft but the poor, the dignitaries and the rich were spared.&lt;br&gt;- Sat:&lt;br&gt;    + authorities allow anyone to stay home for the payment &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;229&quot;/&amp;gt;  of Ps 5 in coins.&lt;br&gt;    + the locust began to fly and arrived in Jerusalem from the east&lt;br&gt;- read in the newspaper &amp;lt;title level=&quot;j&quot;&amp;gt;al-Akhbār&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; from Jaffa&lt;br&gt;- various war news &amp;lt;pb n=&quot;230&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;- in the afternoon flying locusts arrived in Jerusalem and ate many trees. owners of orchards carried measures ....&lt;br&gt;- the price of vegetables sky-rocketed to heights not seen in past years because the locusts are destroying them. There is no delivery but from God.&lt;br&gt;- last Fri: saw a white shirt on sale for Frc 30, which in the past would have cost Frc 40 or 50  </tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="language">Arabic</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="publicationCountry">Bayrūt</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="publisher">Muʾassasat al-Dirasāt al-Filasṭīniyya</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="status">To be reviewed</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="UUID">3C97EB1C-42E8-4972-97DD-D80448AA4114</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="ISBN">9780887283109</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="OCLCID">219448742</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="RIS reference number">219448742</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="All ISBNs">9780887283109 0887283101</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="call-num">015 1033</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="Web data source">WorldCat</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="Standort">OIB</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="Citation identifier">Tamārī 2008a</tss:characteristic>
<tss:characteristic name="URL">http://www.palestine-studies.org/ar/books/%D8%B9%D8%A7%D9%85-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%AC%D8%B1%D8%A7%D8%AF-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%AD%D8%B1%D8%A8-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B9%D8%B8%D9%85%D9%89-%D9%88%D9%85%D8%AD%D9%88-%D8%A7%D9%84%D9%85%D8%A7%D8%B6%D9%8A-%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B9%D8%AB%D9%85%D8%A7%D9%86%D9%8A-%D9%85%D9%86-%D9%81%D9%84%D8%B3%D8%B7%D9%8A%D9%86</tss:characteristic>
</tss:characteristics>
<tss:keywords>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">20th century</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">Borrowed</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">edited source</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">Jerusalem</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">journal/diary</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">Project: Food Riots</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">Source</tss:keyword>
<tss:keyword assigner="Sente User Sebastian">World War I, 1914-18</tss:keyword>
</tss:keywords>
<tss:notes>
<tss:note><title>measures: raṭl</title><comment>In the English translation of an excerpt, published after the Arabic edition, he claims that a raṭl was equal to 3000 gr.</comment><quotation>One raṭl was 2564 gr.</quotation><pages>286</pages></tss:note>
</tss:notes>
<tss:attachments>
<tss:attachmentReference><URL>file:///BachCore/SenteLibrary/BachBibliographie.sente6lib/Contents/Attachments/Tama%CC%84ri%CC%84%2C%20Sali%CC%84m/2008%20%CA%BFa%CC%84m%20al-jara%CC%84d%20al-h%CC%A3arb%20al-%CA%BFuz%CC%A3ma%20wa%20mah%CC%A3w%20al-ma%CC%84d%CC%A3i%CC%84%20al-%CA%BFUthma%CC%84ni%CC%84%20min%20Filast%CC%A3i%CC%84n%20Tama%CC%84ri%CC%84%2C%20Sali%CC%84m.txt</URL></tss:attachmentReference>
</tss:attachments>
</tss:reference>
</tss:references>
</tss:library>
</tss:senteContainer>
